<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Palm Springs Real Estate Video Blog with -- CLIENT NAME --</title>
    <description>Our mission at Will Cook Group is to be your best resource for Palm Springs real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Will Cook Group, your professional Palm Springs Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 14:43:19 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 14:43:19 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The State of Our Local Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QgTI__kzpP0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first statistic I’d like to share with you is our market’s absorption rate, also called months’ supply of inventory, which defines how many months it would take to sell every home that was currently available on the market if no new homes were listed. &lt;strong&gt;As of November 1, our months’ supply of inventory was 3.7 months, which is up 0.7% over last month due to seasonal trends.&lt;/strong&gt; When comparing this number to the same date over the past six years, this is by far the lowest reading, and it’s a sign that the market continues to be a seller’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average days on market in October of 2018 was 64 days, which is 3 days fewer than this same time last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at months of supply in terms of price ranges and comparing each price bracket to this same time last year, the ratio continues to be lower across all brackets. This shows that the market improvements over the last two years spread across all price ranges. That said, it would be nice to see the ratio for homes over $1 million drop down from the current 10.5 months to between eight and nine months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our continued price appreciation and lower inventory make it a great time to consider putting your house on the market in the Greater Palm Springs area.%20localhost:4000/the-state-of-our-local-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our continued price appreciation and lower inventory make it a great time to consider putting your house on the market in the Greater Palm Springs area.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of November 1, Coachella Valley had 3,173 units available in their inventory. This is an increase of 505 units over last month. However, this is a seasonal increase; there are large jumps between October 1 and November 1 every year. &lt;strong&gt;When we compare it to previous November 1 numbers, we see that this is the lowest inventory of the last six years.&lt;/strong&gt; This pattern of each month being the lowest inventory compared to previous years has been occurring for over six months now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increasing strength that we see in the two regional price indices is also showing in city median prices for both detached and attached homes. Changes in the median prices for detached homes show positive numbers that range from a high of 31.3% for Indian Wells down to 4.1% for Cathedral City. In the attached market, four cities—Indio, La Quinta, Palm Springs, and Palm Desert— show double-digit increases, while only Cathedral City has negative changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest rates have continued to slowly increase, and the Federal Reserve is on track to raise rates one more time this year. &lt;strong&gt;This continues to put some urgency on buyers looking to finance so that they can secure properties and lock in an interest rate.&lt;/strong&gt; As rates increase, the number of buyers qualified for the higher price brackets will decrease; this may begin to create a softening effect on pricing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our continued price appreciation and lower inventory make it a great time to consider putting your house on the market in the Greater Palm Springs area. &lt;strong&gt;For buyers who are planning to finance their purchase, there is a little more urgency to get into the market now before rising interest rates negatively affect your purchasing power.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the value of your home or if you’re interested in exploring the possibility of purchasing a property in the Greater Palm Springs area, we’d love to assist you. Please reach to us with any questions you have and for an opportunity to discuss your unique situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-state-of-our-local-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-state-of-our-local-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Palm Springs Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Nuances of Buying in Palm Springs</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/c3yif6f5VLI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of buying a home in the Palm Springs area, you need to be aware of these three nuances:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nuance #1: Location, location, location&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Palm Springs is divided into three main areas: the north end, the central section, and the south end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The north end includes any neighborhood north of Vista Chino. This area features many beautiful mid-century homes and several gated communities, and it’s closely located to the city’s windmills, which means it tends to get more wind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central section is bordered by Vista Chino and Ramon Road. This part of town is very popular due to its proximity to downtown. Not only is it both walkable and bikeable to downtown, but it’s also close to the airport. This section also encompasses some of the most beautiful and expensive neighborhoods in the city, such as Old Las Palmas, Vista Las Palmas, and The Movie Colony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The south end includes any neighborhood south of Ramon Road. This area also has a beautiful collection of neighborhoods and several gated communities, and it also features one of the Valley’s first golf courses: Indian Canyons. This part of town is a particularly popular hiking destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of these three areas, you tend to get more bang for your buck in the north end because of the wind. As I already stated, the biggest advantage of buying in the central portion of town is its proximity to downtown. The south end gets the least amount of wind, but no area is immune from this once it picks up as spring turns into summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Palm Springs is divided into three main areas: the north end, the central section, and the south end.%20localhost:4000/the-nuances-of-buying-in-palm-springs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Palm Springs is divided into three main areas: the north end, the central section, and the south end.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nuance #2: We have lease land&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, this is land you don’t own. It’s not very prevalent throughout the U.S., but we have it here in the Southern California region. In our case, we have two kinds of lease land: contractor’s lease land and land that’s owned by the Agua Caliente tribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the latter case, when the railroad was built in the Palm Springs area in the late 19th century, the government offered the local Agua Caliente tribe 10 miles’ worth of land on both sides of the railroad. Much of this land is still owned by the Agua Caliente tribe, so if you buy a house on that land, you also have to make a lease payment. Typically, a lease-land property can be bought for 20% to 30% less than a comparable home on fee land. However, the lease payment you have to make is not tax deductible, and you’re still responsible for your own property taxes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nuance #3: How you’re going to use the property&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More specifically, do you plan on purchasing a home you want to rent out when you’re not using it? I get a lot of calls from out-of-towners who want to purchase a home and retire here, but they’re not quite ready to start living here permanently yet. They instead opt to buy a home they can rent out that offsets some of the costs until they are ready to move here.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our vacation rental industry is doing very well; however, there are some pretty strong city ordinances regarding rental properties that you need to familiarize yourself with. The other thing you need to consider is that most houses that are located within an HOA neighborhood or a gated community have guidelines determining how long you can rent out your house. In an HOA neighborhood, the minimum rental period is usually 30 days. This means if you plan on turning your home into a weekend vacation rental, you should look outside of HOA neighborhoods. The same 30-day rule generally applies to condos as well, but in both cases, there are some exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to talk more about the nuances of buying a home in Palm Springs, don’t hesitate to pick up the phone and give us a call. We’d love to guide you through the whole process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other real estate questions, feel free to reach out to us as well. We’d be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 13:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/the-nuances-of-buying-in-palm-springs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/the-nuances-of-buying-in-palm-springs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Palm Springs Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top 3 Reasons to Put Your Palm Springs Area Home on the Market this Fall</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xB-yFWpCtx4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our fall market actually presents a number of amazing opportunities for Palm Spring sellers, and today we’ll be highlighting three reasons why putting your property on the market during these later months of the year may be the right next move for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Interest rates are rising.&lt;/strong&gt; The Federal Reserve recently met and raised policy rates by 0.25%. Before that, mortgage rates rose as well. Now, the average interest rate for a single-family home is hovering just below 5%. For condominiums, though, the average rate is now just slightly above 5%. And more rate increases are on the horizon, with one more coming in December of this year and three more expected in 2019. As a result, today’s sellers have the opportunity to capitalize on the sense of urgency spreading among buyers right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Today’s sellers have the opportunity to capitalize on the sense of urgency spreading among buyers right now.%20localhost:4000/top-3-reasons-to-put-your-palm-springs-area-home-on-the-market-this-fall.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Today’s sellers have the opportunity to capitalize on the sense of urgency spreading among buyers right now.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. There will be less competition.&lt;/strong&gt; The majority of Palm Spring homes are vacation properties bought by those looking to take advantage of our gorgeous local weather. While other areas in the country grow cold during the winter months, our Palm Springs area remains nice and warm. So given the fact that people tend to flock here during later months and that September typically sees fewer listings than any other time of year, fall is an ideal time to list here in Palm Springs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The weather starts to break.&lt;/strong&gt; While temperatures are in the triple digits during the summer, they tend to become slightly milder with the arrival of fall. This draws more visitors to our area. And more people means more exposure for your listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 11:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/top-3-reasons-to-put-your-palm-springs-area-home-on-the-market-this-fall.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/top-3-reasons-to-put-your-palm-springs-area-home-on-the-market-this-fall.html</guid>
        
        <category>Palm Springs Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Myths About Your Real Estate Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-IN32Mi1rpE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to take a look at the top three myths about our current real estate market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. We are headed toward another housing bubble&lt;/strong&gt;. Home prices have appreciated year-over-year for the past seventy-six straight months. We are near the peak prices that we saw before the bubble burst previously and many people are worried it will happen again. The reality is, though, that there is a lack of homes for sale and a strong demand for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, a normal market requires six months of inventory for prices to rise with the rate of inflation. Currently, there is only 4.3 months of inventory available, which means that there is still upward pressure on pricing, especially in lower price points. If we see a downturn in the economy with weakening demand, the market will normalize and price gains will be in line with inflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A recession is generally identified by a fall in the GDP for two consecutive quarters and does not equal a housing crisis.%20localhost:4000/3-myths-about-your-real-estate-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A recession is generally identified by a fall in the GDP for two consecutive quarters and does not equal a housing crisis.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The rumored recession will lead to another housing market crash&lt;/strong&gt;. Economists and analysts know that there has been economic growth for nearly a decade, making this the second largest expansion in America’s history. They also know that when this happens, a recession can’t be too far off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recession is generally identified by a fall in the GDP for two consecutive quarters and does not equal a housing crisis. However, many people group them together because the last time there was a recession it caused the housing crisis. According the the Federal Reserve, home values appreciated after five of the last six recessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. There is an affordability crisis&lt;/strong&gt;. The monthly cost of a home is determined by the price that is paid and the interest rate of the mortgage. Even with the current interest rate of 4.59%, according to Zillow, the percentage of median income necessary to buy a home in today’s market is much lower than previously seen. Today’s average of  17.1% is lower than 1985 to 2000’s 21% and lower still than 2006’s 25.4%. Interest rates would have to increase to 6% before buying a home would be less affordable than historic norms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 16:21:44 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-myths-about-your-real-estate-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-myths-about-your-real-estate-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Palm Springs Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Palm Springs Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Quick Update About Your Palm Springs Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-KXhwjZWoj8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is time for another market update. In general, we have continued to be in a strong seller’s market. The months of supply ratio is a figure that measures the balance between supply and demand in real estate. A number of less than 6 months, which is a balanced market, is good for sellers. Meanwhile, any number over six months is good for buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of August 1, our months of supply ratio is 3.2. This is the lowest ratio we have seen since 2013. We can probably expect this number to decrease further over the next couple months before the seasonal forces take affect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The median days on market was 67&lt;/strong&gt;. This is 6.5 days less than it was last year at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above video at 1:12, you can see that the months of supply has improved for each price bracket except for the $700,000 to $800,000 range. All of the ratios below $700,000 are below four months, which is very positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For homes priced over $1 million, months of supply is 8.6 months which is down from 11.6 at the same time last year.&lt;/strong&gt; This figure is a low ratio for that particular price range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The median value of detached homes in each of the nine valley cities show strong 12-month gains. They range from a high 31.4% in Indian Wells to a 3.4% for Palm Springs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Palm Springs, which has been the price leader in the region for the last three years appears to be temporarily slowing down.%20localhost:4000/a-quick-update-about-your-palm-springs-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Palm Springs, which has been the price leader in the region for the last three years appears to be temporarily slowing down.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Palm Springs, which has been the price leader in the region for the last three years appears to be temporarily slowing down. Meanwhile, other cities such as Palm Desert, Rancho Mirage, and Indian Wells seem to be playing catch-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest rates have continued to climb and the Federal Reserve is on track to make two more increases this year. The first of which will be at their September 20th meeting. This has put some urgency on buyers to secure properties so that they can lock in on an interest rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As interest rates increase, the number of buyers qualified for higher brackets will decrease&lt;/strong&gt;. This may begin to create some softening effect on pricing in the higher tax brackets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our continued price appreciation and lower inventory point is a great time to consider selling your greater Palm Springs area home. If you are a buyer who is financing your purchase, there is more urgency to get in the market now before the interest rates impact your purchasing power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the value of your home or you are interested in buying in the Palm Springs area, please feel free to contact me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 13:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/a-quick-update-about-your-palm-springs-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/a-quick-update-about-your-palm-springs-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Palm Springs Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips to Become a Successful Vacation Rental Owner</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8PdYHYbmBQA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am coming at you from one of my new listings (a beautiful vacation rental with three bedrooms and two bathrooms) to ask, “How can you be successful with vacation rentals in the Palm Springs area?” Recently I received three tips from property managers helping explain how to be successful and I thought I would share them with you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=From your linens to your toiletries, whatever you offer guests should be similar to that of a five-star hotel.%20localhost:4000/3-tips-to-become-a-successful-vacation-rental-owner.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“From your linens to your toiletries, whatever you offer guests should be similar to that of a five-star hotel.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, however, I want to talk about measure C which was voted on banning vacation rentals. This measure was specifically for single-family homes in Palm Springs that are not in HOAs since the HOA rules take precedence over city ordinance. However, by a 2/3 majority vote, that vacation rental ban did not happen, leaving vacation rentals alive and well in our area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Think high-end hotel.&lt;/strong&gt; From your linens to your toiletries, whatever you offer guests should be similar to that of a five-star hotel. You should provide ample linens so your guests do not feel obligated to wash anything during their stay. Supply shampoo, toothpaste, mints, etc. to your guests for the bathroom as well as coffee, tea, soft drinks, and bottled water for the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Storage area&lt;/strong&gt;. Have your own basic storage space for your house supplies and personal belongings. You could have a locked closet in the master or use a spare hallway closet. This gives you space for supplies for not only the house, but for you if you ever plan on staying there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Welcome booklet.&lt;/strong&gt; Create a welcome booklet for guests that gives instructions on how to use anything technical in the home such as the televisions, audio equipment, or alarm system. This helps prevent them from having to call you personally or your property manager. You should also include any house rules or community ordinances. And, you can even add local attractions and restaurant recommendations for the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions, are interested in buying the lovely home seen in the video, or are looking at selling your own home, please feel free to contact me. I would be happy to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 14:54:34 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/3-tips-to-become-a-successful-vacation-rental-owner.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/3-tips-to-become-a-successful-vacation-rental-owner.html</guid>
        
        <category>Palm Springs Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Palm Springs Homebuyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Real Estate Remains Hot, Aside From the Luxury Market Segment</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3GJcn2mI5BY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you saw in my last market update for Palm Springs, the real estate market remains red-hot. Palm Springs has actually surpassed its all-time high in the single-family market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, Zillow estimates that homes sold more quickly in 2017 than ever before. Meanwhile 2018 seems on pace to beat 2017. However, there is one segment of the real estate market seems to be lagging.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I’m talking about the luxury home market.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Prices in the top 5% of the real estate market increased just 5.1% in 2017, which is a full 2% lower than the rest of the market. What’s going on?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Affordability does not seem to be an issue, as more Americans can afford a top-level home than ever before. Instead, it might come down to two other contributing factors.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, uncertainty surrounding the new tax bill could be affecting luxury homes more strongly,&lt;/strong&gt; and this might be the reason why some potential buyers are choosing to sit and wait until the details of the new tax bill become more clear for their specific situation. Second, there is simply a greater supply of luxury homes than in any other market segment. In fact, 53% of available housing inventory is in the premium market, compared to 23% for the start-up market and 24% for the trade-up homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Demand and supply are more evenly matched at the top of the market.%20localhost:4000/real-estate-remains-hot-aside-from-the-luxury-market-segment.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Demand and supply are more evenly matched at the top of the market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In other words, supply outstrips demand at the top of the market, while in other segments, demand far outstrips supply. What does all of this mean for you?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you’ve been thinking about trading up to a luxury home, now might be the perfect time to do so. &lt;strong&gt;The red-hot demand for starter and trade-up homes mean you could sell your home for top dollar and in record time.&lt;/strong&gt; The limited price growth and greater inventory at the luxury end means you could have your pick, and find a special, unique, customized home that perfectly suits your needs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions about the current Palm Springs real estate market, what your home is worth, and what’s out there, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 13:34:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/real-estate-remains-hot-aside-from-the-luxury-market-segment.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/real-estate-remains-hot-aside-from-the-luxury-market-segment.html</guid>
        
        <category>Palm Springs Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Important Update for the Palm Springs Area Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5hkVbR7FMhQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time for a market update. Let’s take a look at how current conditions are contributing to rising prices and declining supply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://will.palmspringsarea.properties/index.php?types[]=1&amp;amp;types[]=2&amp;amp;areas[]=city%3APalm+Springs&amp;amp;fbts=3108061&amp;amp;beds=0&amp;amp;baths=0&amp;amp;min=0&amp;amp;max=30000000&amp;amp;map=0&amp;amp;options[]=new&amp;amp;sortby=listings.listingdate+DESC&amp;amp;quick=1&amp;amp;ppc=VyralVideoBlog_Buyers&amp;amp;addht=VyralVideoBlog_Buyers#rslt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.topproducer.com/pages/index.html?pageid=a237f3ff-79a3-40c9-96d2-a3ad8cda13ac&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s going on in our local real estate market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, we’ve been in a strong seller’s market recently. This can be determined by looking at the “months of supply” ratio, which measures the balance of supply and demand. In this case, supply refers to our current available inventory while demand refers to sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A balance of low supply and high demand is what leads us to a seller’s market in the realm of real estate.&lt;/strong&gt; Our current ratio, which is at 4.2 months, is the lowest May 1 figure we’ve seen since 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the average number of days on market this April was 64—the lowest figure for that month in the last five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Returning to the subject of supply, let’s discuss how price range can impact these figures. For all price brackets below $700,000, the months of supply ratio is below six months. Homes at and above the $800,000 price point have experienced considerable improvement in terms of supply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=NOW IS A GREAT TIME TO ENTER THE MARKET.%20localhost:4000/an-important-update-for-palm-springs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“NOW IS A GREAT TIME TO ENTER THE MARKET.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inventory, though, continues to shrink overall. As of May 1, there were 3,622 units available on our market. This is 870 fewer units than were on the market at this time last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diminishing inventory is one half of what’s been driving up home prices, recently.&lt;/strong&gt; And if typical seasonal patterns persist, inventory is likely to continue its decline until September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a closer look at appreciation, Cathedral City, Palm Springs, and Palm Desert stand out as the three local cities with the greatest price momentum for detached homes. These cities have 12-month gains of 15.6%, 12.7%, and 11.8% respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Palm Springs has been the region leader in terms of price, with a current median of $656,100. &lt;strong&gt;This is 9.3% above the previous all-time high we saw in 2006.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of these considerations in mind, now is a great time to enter the market. Sellers have a great opportunity to take advantage of current market conditions. Buyers considering using financing to purchase a home are facing some urgency at the moment, though, as the impending rise of interest rates will negatively impact purchasing power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 15:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/an-important-update-for-palm-springs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/an-important-update-for-palm-springs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Palm Springs Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Reasons Your Insurance Company Will Drop You</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6QGdQSbofyc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of things that could prompt your insurance company to drop your coverage. Today, I’ll be going over four common reasons this can happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://will.palmspringsarea.properties/index.php?types[]=1&amp;amp;types[]=2&amp;amp;areas[]=city%3APalm+Springs&amp;amp;fbts=3108061&amp;amp;beds=0&amp;amp;baths=0&amp;amp;min=0&amp;amp;max=30000000&amp;amp;map=0&amp;amp;options[]=new&amp;amp;sortby=listings.listingdate+DESC&amp;amp;quick=1&amp;amp;ppc=VyralVideoBlog_Buyers&amp;amp;addht=VyralVideoBlog_Buyers#rslt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.topproducer.com/pages/index.html?pageid=a237f3ff-79a3-40c9-96d2-a3ad8cda13ac&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homeowners usually see their payments to the home insurance company as a necessary evil. The coverage they offer protects your home, your belongings, and your investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, shelling out thousands to an insurance company can hit your wallet hard. It may seem like a large financial burden, but did you know that an insurance company can choose to drop you altogether?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Violating the terms of your agreement, not paying your premiums, or committing fraud are all examples of how this can happen. But, your coverage can also be jeopardized for other reasons. If your insurer feels you or your home are too risky to cover, you could have a hard time finding another company that will provide you with coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’d like to share four common reasons an insurance company will drop you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. You have an old roof.&lt;/strong&gt; This might surprise you, but having an old roof can prompt your insurance company to ask you to replace it. If you don’t, they may drop your coverage. The average lifespan of a roof is 30 years. After that length of time, your roof will become more susceptible to issues like water damage. Since water damage is the most commonly submitted home insurance claim, insurance companies want to ensure your home is not at risk. Nevertheless, age alone won’t trigger a non-renewal. If your insurance company notices issues with your roof, you can expect a letter asking that you make repairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=DON’T USE YOUR INSURANCE POLICY AS A MAINTENANCE POLICY BY FILING CLAIMS THAT BARELY MEET YOUR DEDUCTIBLE.%20localhost:4000/4-reasons-your-insurance-company-will.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“DON’T USE YOUR INSURANCE POLICY AS A MAINTENANCE POLICY BY FILING CLAIMS THAT BARELY MEET YOUR DEDUCTIBLE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. You have too many claims.&lt;/strong&gt; This might sound unfair, but it happens. Insurance companies will most likely drop a policy if you file more than one claim in the same policy term. Insurance is based on averages. The average consumer files a claim every nine or 10 years. So if you file more than that, the insurance company won’t see you as profitable. Pay close attention to how often you file claims, especially if you bundle your insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. They don’t want to cover a specific area.&lt;/strong&gt; This might happen if the insurance company is finding that too many claims are coming in from a certain area or state. If your area is prone to crime, flooding, or fires, the insurance company may decide to cease coverage. Thankfully, there are other ways to pursue coverage if this happens to you. You can always discuss your options with an independent broker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. They have an issue with your pets.&lt;/strong&gt; Insurance companies may exclude certain pets from their policies. If your pet is exotic or considered high-risk, this may pose a problem for your coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of these things in mind, remember that there are steps you can take to stay in your insurance company’s good graces. Perform regular maintenance and make necessary repairs as soon as you become aware of them. Don’t use your insurance policy as a maintenance policy by filing claims that barely meet your deductible. Have money set aside for regular maintenance and repairs, and save your insurance for major issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 13:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/4-reasons-your-insurance-company-will.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/4-reasons-your-insurance-company-will.html</guid>
        
        <category>Palm Springs Insurance</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Boost Your Homes Value With These 4 Steps</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/k5RXk_Rl9Dg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four steps you can take in order to prepare your home to sell for top dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Buying a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://will.palmspringsarea.properties/index.php?types[]=1&amp;amp;types[]=2&amp;amp;areas[]=city%3APalm+Springs&amp;amp;fbts=3108061&amp;amp;beds=0&amp;amp;baths=0&amp;amp;min=0&amp;amp;max=30000000&amp;amp;map=0&amp;amp;options[]=new&amp;amp;sortby=listings.listingdate+DESC&amp;amp;quick=1&amp;amp;ppc=VyralVideoBlog_Buyers&amp;amp;addht=VyralVideoBlog_Buyers#rslt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to perform a full home search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Selling a home? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.topproducer.com/pages/index.html?pageid=a237f3ff-79a3-40c9-96d2-a3ad8cda13ac&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every seller wants to get as much money as possible for their home, but few know how to accomplish this. As it turns out, there are four steps you can take to prepare your home to sell for top dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Do the ordinary updates.&lt;/strong&gt; These updates include replacing rotten wood, taking care of a leaky roof, getting rid of mold, and remediating other water intrusion issues. It’s also a good idea to put a new coat of paint on the walls. Buyers tend to look over houses very carefully, so it’s important to check out every inch of your home and update what you can without breaking the bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Consider remodeling or updating your kitchen.&lt;/strong&gt; If it looks dated, repaint the walls, install a new backsplash, and purchase new, energy-efficient appliances. If you’re going to repaint, consider using low VOC paint, as it has fewer harsh chemicals and is more eco-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A GREAT OUTDOOR SPACE CAN MAKE OR BREAK A SALE.%20localhost:4000/boost-your-homes-value-with-these-4.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A GREAT OUTDOOR SPACE CAN MAKE OR BREAK A SALE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Improve your outdoor environment.&lt;/strong&gt; A great outdoor space can make or break a sale, especially here in the greater Palm Springs area, where we enjoy so many months of incredible weather. Update your landscaping by installing drought-tolerant flowering plants or perhaps an outdoor seating area. For larger projects, you might want to consider creating a covered outdoor entertainment space, or possibly some hardscaping with pavers and a firepit. If your pool needs cleaning or resurfacing, go ahead and do that. Additionally, be sure to take advantage of any views that your property has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Prioritize energy efficiency.&lt;/strong&gt; More buyers today than ever are looking for energy-efficient installments. To take advantage of this, consider replacing your windows, buying Energy Star appliances, or installing LED canned lighting. These features are not only appealing to prospective buyers, but they can also lower your energy bills while you’re still living in the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this or other real estate topics, please feel free to give me a call or send a text or email. I’d be happy to answer them for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 10:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>localhost:4000/boost-your-homes-value-with-these-4.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">localhost:4000/boost-your-homes-value-with-these-4.html</guid>
        
        <category>Palm Springs Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
